ILGWU Justice on Microfilm 5780/051 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Justice on Microfilm
1919-1982
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/051 mf
6.22 cubic feet
56 microfilm reels
Publications, microfilm.
Microfilm copies of issues of the publication Justice.
6323217
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 08, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 08, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Justice was the official organ of the ILGWU from 1919 to 1995. Editions of Justice were published in English, Italian, Spanish, and Yiddish. When compared side by side, the content of some of these different editions of Justice shows significant differences.
Scope and Contents
Negative copies available upon request
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/051 PUBS: ILGWU Publications Justice 5780/180: ILGWU Publication "Justice" Index
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Textile workers -- New York (State) -- New York; Textile workers -- United States
6323217
- Justice: vols.1-3, 1919-1921 (Reel 8)
- Justice: vols.4-6, 1922-1924 (Reel 10)
- Justice: vols.6-8, 1924-1926 (Reel 11)
- Justice: vols.9-14, 1927-1932 (Reel 13)
- Justice: vols.15-19, 1933-1937 (Reel 14)
- Justice: vols.20-23, 1938-1941 (Reel 15)
- Justice: vols.23-26, 1941-1944 (Reel 16)
- Justice: vols.27-30, 1945-1948 (Reel 17)
- Justice: vols.31-34, 1949-1952 (Reel 18)
- Justice: vols.35-37, 1953-1955 (Reel 19)
- Justice: vols.38-40, 1956-1958 (Reel 20)
- Justice: vols.41-42, 1959-1960 (Reel 21)
- Justice - vol. 43, 1961 (Reel 42)
- Justice - vol. 44, 1962 (Reel 43)
- Justice - vol 45, 1963 (Reel 44)
- Justice: vols.46-48, 1964-1966 (Reel 22)
- Justice: vols.49-50, 1967-1968 (Reel 23)
- Justice: vols.51-54, 1969-1972 (Reel 24)
- Justice: vols.55-56, 1973-1974 (Reel 26)
- Justice: vols.57-58, 1975-1976 (Reel 27)
- Justice: vol.59, 1977 (Reel 28)
- Justice: vol.60, 1978 (Reel 29)
- Justice: vol.61, 1979 (Reel 30)
- Justice: vol.62, 1980 (Reel 31)
- Justice: vol.63, 1981 (Reel 32)
- Justice: vol.64, 1982 (Reel 33)